EUROPEAN CV FORMAT



Profile

Software engineer with ten years of experience in different kinds of companies like building materials, insurance, IT outsourcing, and software factories. Responsible, proactive, honest, enthusiastic, and committed person. Adaptability to the change, solving problems efficiently, and achieving the goals proposed by the company and workgroup.

My experience has allowed me to increase my abilities in all phases of the software development lifecycle like analysis, design, implementation, continuous integration, and continuous deployment. In addition, I have solid experience working with JAVA, Cloud, Microservices, Containerization, and DevOps. Strong knowledge using design and architectural patterns, OOP, TDD.

Good relations with colleagues and customers, ability to listen and explain my ideas clearly. I am always willing to learn new skills.

Mobile phone +57 315-7441000

Email <u>Jdrodriguez152855@gmail.com</u>

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lead Software Engineer (Key Developer at Atlassian), EPAM Anywhere, October 2021 - Current

Name and address of employer

Type of Business

Main activities and responsibilities

Medellín - Colombia.

IT Outsourcing

- Develop new APIs to support functionalities in the process to claim user
- accounts..
- Fix security breaches in different components to support Jira and Confluence customers.
- Develop internal JAVA libraries to be used by multiple components across the company.
- Implement enhancements to add new features and to increase the performance of the existing components.
- Reduce technical debt in some JAVA components.
- Maintain good communication and constant synchronization with the Product Owner and Scrum Master.

Technologies

JAVA, JAVA Reactive with Project Reactor, SPRINGBOOT, AWS (EC2, S3, DynamoDB, SQS, SNS, RDS, CloudWatch), GIT, MAVEN, BITBUCKET PIPELINES, Atrifactory, LaunchDarkly, SPLINK

 ${\bf PIPELINES, A trifactory, Launch Darkly, SPLUNK.}$

Full-stack Developer, LafargeHolcim, February 2021 - October 2021

Name and address of employer

Type of Business

Main activities and responsibilities

Medellín - Colombia. Building materials

- Design and develop software in different languages/technologies like JAVA, AWS, SPRINGBOOT, and MYSQL to support cement customer operations.
- Design technical solutions to guarantee the integral achievement of business requirements and technical attributes such as quality, availability, security, elasticity, and simplicity.
- Implement enhancements to add new features and to increase the performance of the existing components.
- Propose solutions for different issues discovered during technical support.
- Guarantee a software development process with high technical and quality standards inside the team.
- Maintain good communication and constant synchronization with the Product Owner and Scrum Master.

Technologies

JAVA, SPRINGBOOT, AWS (Cognito, EC2, ECS, ECR, S3, CodeDeploy, RDS), MYSQL, LIQUIBASE, GIT, BITBUCKET PIPELINES.

Technology Development Analyst (Technical Designer), Suramericana de Seguros, January 2016 - February 2021

Name and address of employer

Medellín - Colombia.

Type of Business

Main activities and responsibilities

Insurance

- Design technical solutions in an appropriate way, guaranteeing the integral achievement of business requirements and technical attributes: quality, availability, security, elasticity, and simplicity.
- Guarantee a software development process with high technical and quality standards inside the team.
- Design and develop software systems in different technologies like JAVA, SCALA, and PL/SQL to support new products related to insurance.
- Modify existing software to correct errors, adapt it to new hardware, or upgrade interfaces and improve performance.
- Guarantee the articulation of the team with the defined process of architecture, quality, infrastructure, and DevOps in the company.
- Manage technical dependencies with other teams of the company or external teams of IT Outsourcing.
- Maintain good communication and constant synchronization with the Product Owner and Scrum Master.

Technologies

JAVA, SCALA, WEBLOGIC, ORACLE, PLSQL, AWS, AZURE, DOCKER, KUBERNETES, MICROSERVICES, GIT, GRADLE, JIRA, SONAR, and JENKINS

Mid-level Development Engineer, Intergrupo, July 2015 - January 2016

Name and address of employer

Medellín - Colombia.

Type of Business

Technology - Outsourcing at SURA

Main activities and responsibilities

- Design and develop software systems in different technologies like JAVA and PL/SQL to support new products related to insurance.
- Modify existing software to correct errors, adapt it to new hardware, or upgrade interfaces and improve performance.
- Contribute to all phases of the development lifecycle from analysis to maintenance.

- Ensure that development tasks finish within the timeline provided and deliver with high technical quality.

JAVA, WEBLOGIC, ORACLE, PLSQL

Technologies

Software Engineering Analyst, MVM Ingenieria de software, July 2014 - July 2015

Name and address of employer Medellín - Colombia.

Type of Business Technology – Outsourcing at EPM

Main activities and responsibilities - Verify and solve the requirements or complaints created by customers related to

failures in different applications.

- Modify existing software to correct errors, adapt it to new hardware

specifications, or redesign interfaces to improve performance.

- Prepare and present monthly reports on the number of incidents, gravity, impact,

and solutions of them.

Technologies - Propose solutions for different errors discovered during technical support.

JAVA, JAVASCRIPT, JQUERY, JBOSS, ORACLE, CSS

Software Developer, Termotecnica Coindustrial, August 2013 - July 2014

Name and address of employer San José de Cúcuta - Colombia.

Type of business Oil Pipeline Maintenance

Main activities and responsibilities - Design and develop software systems in JAVA for supporting

operations of the company.

- Verify and solve the requirements or complaints created by customers in relation

to failures in different applications.

- Execute maintenance of existing hardware and software in different locations...

- Generate reports on different applications for different departments like

accounting, recruiting, and billing.

Technologies JAVA, JAVASCRIPT, MYSQL, JASPER REPORT

Junior Software Developer, Gnosoft Ltda, March 2012 - August 2013

Name and address of employer San José de Cúcuta - Colombia.

Type of business Software Factory

Main activities and responsibilities - Design and develop new functionalities on Gnosoft Academico software.

- Contribute to all phases of the development lifecycle from analysis to

maintenance.

- Verify and solve the requirements or complaints created by customers related to

failures in Gnosoft Academico software.

Technologies - Propose solutions for different errors discovered during support.

JAVA, TOMCAT, JSP, JAVASCRIPT, POSTGRE SQL

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

BCS in Systems Engineering, Francisco de Paula Santander University, From 2005 to 2013

Main subjects covered Software Development 1, 2,3,4 and 5; Database Administration, Software Engineering 1, 2 and

3; Electronic 1,2,3; Physic 1,2 and 3; Calculus 1,2,3 4 and 5;

(If proceeds) National classification

level

College

Azure Fundamentals, AZ-900

Training Organization Microsoft Main subjects covered Azure

(If proceeds) National classification

level

Certification, Number: H458-2744

Kubernetes, beginner to expert

Training Organization Udemy

Page 3 - Curriculum vitae from [RODRIGUEZ GUTIERREZ, Jesus]

For more information:

www.linkedin.com/in/jesus-david-rodriguez-gutierrez-48a120b8

Main subjects covered

(If proceeds) National classification level

Kubernetes

Certification, Number: UC-ed1be719-383c-4933-b495-c66f107ff515

GCP learning path

Training Organization

Main subjects covered

Qwiklabs GCP

(If proceeds) National classification

level

https://google.qwiklabs.com/public_profiles/42b9b025-51c8-478a-9131-8614efd9fcf2

PERSONAL SKILLS AND

COMPETENCES

NATIVE LANGUAGE OTHER LANGUAGES

SPANISH, NATIVE COMPETITIVE

English B2, Certificated by SMART ACADEMY, Medellin, Colombia

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND COMPETENCES

Programming languages: JAVA (1.6, 1.8, 11) and Reactive Programming, SCALA, PL/SQL

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB, and Oracle.

Technologies, frameworks, tools: Springboot, Project Reactor, Thymeleaf, Liquibase, Jenkins, Gradle, SonarQube, RunDeck, Artifactory, SBT, Bitbucket pipelines, Maven, Codacy,

Junit, SOAPUI, Postman, and JMeter.

Version Control Systems: Git

IDEs: IntelliJ Idea, Eclipse, and Spring Tool Suite **Server applications:** Apache Tomcat, Netty, Web Logic.

Cloud: AWS, Azure, GCP Container: Docker, Kubernetes Agile methodology: Scrum, Kanban

Knowledge: Design and architectural patterns, SOLID principles, CI/CD.

ARTISTIC SKILLS AND COMPETENCES

I love playing football and tennis; I try to practice them at least once a week. I enjoy nature, hiking, and discovering new landscapes. I am good at solving logical

problems like puzzles.